regenerative design is about creating
elegant solutions that are carefully
adapted to the bio cultural uniqueness
of place it is about working with people
in place to unleash the latent potential
of local communities to work towards
increase health wholeness and resilience
at the community and the regional level
this means increasing the health of our
soils it means establishing regenerative
agricultural systems that increase bio
productivity and agricultural
biodiversity it means increasing the
amount of standing forests in a region
for by a protective biosphere reserves
but at the same time it also means
building forests analog forests that can
supply the biomaterials for the
circularly focused regionally focused
biomaterials economies of the future
that will be driven by renewable
energies but beyond that regenerative
development is also a personal
development process that by working on
ourselves we work on our capacity to be
more able to collaborate in these
regenerative business ecologies that
work on collaborative abundance rather
than competitive scarcity it is about
creating opportunities for personal
growth and for increased social cohesion
by working by increasing collaborative
abundance and at its most audacious
regenerative development promises us the
opportunity to redesign the human
presence on earth from being by and
large destructive and exploitative to
being predominantly regenerative at its
most humble regenerative design reminds
us that we just don't know that we are
living in a fundamentally interconnected
constantly transforming process of which
we are part and which we bring forth
through the way we see the world and the
way we act and
and the only way that we can create a
regenerative future of diverse
regenerative cultures carefully adapted
to the uniqueness of the places they
inhabit is by increasing collaborative
abundance and by fundamentally
understanding that as life our job is to
create conditions conducive to life that
if we do so if we work on the health and
wholeness of the planetary system it
will support the community of life and
it will support the human community the
only way to move forward the only way to
implement the agenda 2030 and meet all
the 17 sustainable development goals is
by engaging in this kind of regenerative
development it is a win-win-win process
of working towards a regenerative future
for all so I hope you join us in this
amazing endeavor in this opportunity for
Humanity to fundamentally redesign its
impact on the planet thank you